杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们告诉盖茨比要一具尸体,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: We told
Gatsby to expect a body,
但我们还没这么做。
but we haven't done that yet.
原因是并不是所有的节点类型
And the reason for
that is that not all of the node types
当我们开始创建节点的时候，问题就完全解决了。
fully resolved by the time
we get to on create node.
所以这就产生了一个挑战。
And so that creates a challenge.
如果我想得到 MDX 的身体,
If I wanna get the MDX body,
就是那种我们可以在站点上显示 MDX 的经过处理的代码。
which is that kind of processed code that
we can use on a site to display MDX.
我不能就这么说，还没定呢。
I can't just call it here, it's not set.
这意味着我必须创建一个自定义解析器。
So that means that I have to
create a custom resolver.
这就是我们进入有趣部分的地方,
And so this is where we're kind
of getting into the fun part,
盖茨比工作方式的真正细节。
the really nitty gritty
of how Gatsby works.
所以我们要继续创建自定义解析器。
So we're gonna go ahead and
create the custom resolver.
我们使用 createresolver API 钩子,
And we do that using
the createresolver API hook,
这就给了我们，不好意思，这是复数创造者。
which gives us, sorry,
it's plural createresolvers.
这就给了我们一个叫做 createresolvers 的函数。
And that gives us a function
called createresolvers.
我们称之为。
And we call that.
如果你以前用过 GraphQL,
And if you've ever used GraphQL before,
解析器的工作方式是反映数据结构。
the way that resolvers work is
they reflect the data structure.
因此，如果你有一个类型的文档页面，你可以
So if you have a type of docs page,
you can
通过创建一个以 docs 页面作为对象键的对象来定义解析器，以及
define resolvers by creating an object
that has docs page as the object key, and
然后字段名作为子对象。
then a field name as a sub-object.
默认情况下，它会查找节点，所以
By default, what it'll do is
it'll look for the node, so
我们正在创建的文档页面节点。
this docs page node that we're creating.
它会在该节点上说，给我与字段名匹配的属性。
And it will say on that node, give me
the property that matches the field name.
所以对于 title，它会寻找 node.title。
So for title, it'll look for node.title.
在这些情况下，对于在路径中更新的 ID 标题，这就是我们想要的。
And in these cases, for the ID title
updated in path, that's what we want.
我们需要默认行为。
We want the default behavior.
所以我们不需要修改它。
So we don't need to modify that.
解析器将按预期工作。
Resolvers will work as expected.
但是尸体，我们这里没有尸体。
But for body,
we don't have a body on here.
所以我们需要改变这种状况。
So we need to change that.
这意味着我们需要做一些事情。
And that means that we need
to do a couple things.
所以首先，我们需要准备一些东西，我刚刚意识到我忘记了
So first, we need to set up a couple
things that I just realized I forgot when
我很兴奋要安排这件事。
I got excited about setting this thing up.
所以在 createNode 调用中，每个 Gatsby 节点都需要有这个内部字段。
So in a createNode call, every Gatsby
node needs to have this internal field.
记住，我们一分钟前谈过这个问题。
Remember, we talked
about that a minute ago.
它包括类型名称和诸如此类的东西。
It includes the type name and
those sorts of things.
所以我们要设置类型，我们只需要使用 DocsPage。
So we're gonna set up the type and
we'll just use DocsPage.
再说一次，这可以是我们想要的任何东西，我们只是想确保它是独一无二的。
Again, this can be whatever we want,
we just wanna make sure that it's unique.
您可以在这里做一些聪明的事情，以保证有一个唯一的类型名称。
You could do something clever in here
to have a guaranteed unique type name.
但除非你要建一个真正复杂的盖茨比工地,
But unless you're doing a really
really complex Gatsby site,
这很容易管理。
this is pretty easy to manage.
接下来我们需要的是，我们总是想给它一个内容摘要。
And the next thing that we need is we
always wanna give it a content digest.
因为 Gatsby 使用内容摘要，它类似于节点内容的散列
Because Gatsby uses the content digest,
which is like a hash of the node content
来决定它是否应该扔掉那个节点，建立一个新的节点。
to decide whether or not it should throw
away that node and build a new one.
这是一种在构建过程中减少工作量的方法。
That's a way to do less
work during the build.
所以在这种情况下,
So, in this case,
我们实际上不需要创建一个，因为我们只是使用 MDX 节点。
we don't really need to create one
because we're just using an MDX node.
所以我们只需要使用这个节点的内容摘要
So we'll just use that
node's content digest, so
我们不需要做额外的工作。
we don't have to do any extra work.
因为如果 MDX 节点发生更改，文档页面将发生更改。
Because if our MDX node changes,
our docs page will change.
这是一个相当安全的假设。
That's a fairly safe assumption.
现在我们有了这些，这些内部的和类型，我们可以实际使用它们。
Now that we've got these, these internal
and type, we can actually use them.
所以在我们的 createResolvers 中，我们将进入我们的 DocsPage 类型,
So in our createResolvers we're
going to get into our DocsPage type,
然后我们要建立一个身体解析器。
and then we're gonna
set up a body resolver.
因此，像这样的解析器中的主体类型声明有两个属性。
So, a body type declaration in
a resolver like this has two properties.
第一个是一个类型，这和我们在这里的声明相匹配。
The first one is a type, and so that's
gonna match our declaration up here.
让我把这些折叠起来，这样更容易移动。
Let me collapse these down so
it's easier to move between.
我们得到了我们的身体，这是一条线，它是必需的。
We've got our body,
which is a string and it's required.
在这里，我们要说它是一个字符串，它是必需的。
So in here, we're gonna say it's
a string and it's required.
然后我们有一个叫做解决的属性。
And then we have
a property called resolve.
这是一个函数。
And that is a function.
这样就有了四个参数。
So that gets four arguments.
这是一个非常标准的 GraphQL 模式。
This is a pretty standard GraphQL pattern.
第一个参数是实际的数据，也就是节点本身。
The first argument is the actual data,
so the node itself.
然后将所有参数传递给该节点。
Then you get any arguments
passed to that node.
所以如果你有一个过滤器或当我们使用日期格式，如果我们
So if you had a filter or
when we're using the date format if we
想要设置如何格式化的东西，这会出现在这个 args 的论点。
wanna set how to format things,
that would come in this args argument.
然后我们获得上下文，即关于请求或节点的信息。
Then we get context, which is information
about the request or the node.
最后，我们得到了一些信息，这是很普遍的
And finally, we get info,
which is kind of general
关于 GraphQL Schema 的信息以及我们可能正在做的所有事情。
information about the GraphQL Schema and
all the things that we might be doing.
因为我们正在深入了解盖茨比的内心世界,
And because we are diving
into the internals of Gatsby,
我们要把这四个都用上。
we are gonna use all four of those.
通常情况下，你会发现很多时候你只是使用源代码。
Typically, you'll find a lot of
times you'll just use the source.
但是当你开始做这些有趣的事情的时候，它就会变得有点不靠谱了。
But when you get into these kind of fun
things, it will get a little wonky.
所以我们要做的第一件事是，我们要加载 MDX 的解析器
So the first thing we wanna do is we
wanna load the resolver for the MDX
特别是我们要找到尸体。
type, and
specifically we want the body field.
所以我们通过创建一个新的常量
So we do that by creating
a new constant and
我们只需要执行 info.schema.getType (‘ mdx’)。
we'll just do info.schema.getType ('mdx').
然后在下面我们会得到所有的 mdxFields。
And then below that we're going
to get all the mdxFields.
这将是 getFields 类型。
And that's going to be type getFields.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们现在所做的就是在《了不起的盖茨比》中所说的
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So what we've done
right now is we've said in the Gatsby
在整个模式中，我们希望加载 MDX 节点的整个模式定义。
schema, the whole schema, we want to load
the whole schema definition for MDX nodes.
这就给了我们自己的类型。
That gives us our type.
然后我们要装载 MDX 的所有字段，这就给出了字段。
So then we're gonna load all of the fields
for MDX and that gives us the field.
所以除了其他的事情，它会给我们提供身体场。
So among other things,
it will give us that body field.
然后我要找到解决方案。
And then I wanna get the resolver for it.
我通过获取 mdxFields.body.resolve 来做到这一点。
And I do that by getting
mdxFields.body.resolve.
这个解析的定义方式与这个解析的定义方式相同。
And this resolve is defined
the same way as this one is.
所以我们的意思是,
So what we're basically saying is,
我希望能够解决对文档页面主体类型的请求,
I want to be able to resolve
the request to the docs page body type,
与我们将 MDX 节点请求解析为主体类型的方法完全相同。
exactly the same way as we resolve
MDX node request to the body type.
这说得通吗？
Does that make sense?
所以我们所做的就是通过解析器。
So what we've done in doing this is
we've made a pass through resolver.
这意味着我们的文档页面将处理
And that means that our docs page
is going to handle requests for
Mdx 数据与 MDX 的方式完全相同。
MDX data exactly the same way as MDX does.
我们不是重造轮子，我们也不是在重新实现 MDX。
And we're not reinventing the wheel,
we're not re-implementing MDX.
我们只是在使用 MDX 已经在做的工作。
We're just using the work
that MDX is already doing.
一旦我们有了这个解析器我们就可以得到 mdxNode,
So once we've got this resolver,
we can I get the mdxNode,
通过进入上下文来实现。
which will do by going into the context.
我们将进入 nodeModel 并通过它的 ID 获取节点。
And we'll go into the nodeModel and
get the node by its ID.
Id 是父节点，因为记住我们的文档页面,
And the ID is the parent node
because remember our docs page,
设置一个，还是我说的父母？
set a, or did I said a parent?
希望如此。
I hope I did.
我有父母。
I have the parent.
但不是我设置的。
But I didn't set it.
那么，让我们也设置一下。
So let's set that as well.
因此，我们将设置，Jason Lengstorf: Node id 为
So we will set the,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Node id of
我们的 MDX 节点作为我们的 DocsPage 节点的父节点，所以
our MDX node as the parent
of our DocsPage node so
我们可以在这个解析器中引用它。
that we're able to reference
that in this resolver.
因此，拥有这个源 node.parent 意味着我们可以提取 MDX 节点本身。
So having this source node.parent means
that we can pull out the MDX node itself.
加载此 MDX 节点后，现在就可以解析它了。
Once we've loaded this MDX node,
we can now just resolve it.
所以我们要运行这个解析器函数，这个函数是我们从 MDX 体字段中提取出来的。
So we're gonna run this resolver function
that we pulled out of the MDX body field.
我们的参数是想从中获取数据的 mdxNode,
And our arguments are the mdxNode
that we wanna get data from,
如果我们想要通过的话，那些方舟就会通过,
the args that were passed in in
case we wanted to do pass through,
请求的上下文以备不时之需。
the context of the request
in case that's needed.
然后我们要告诉超能力者，我们正在使用身体场。
And then we just wanna tell the meta
that we're using the body field.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 既然我们已经做到了,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So
now that we've done that,
我们应该做的是查询
what we should be able to do is query for
我们的文档页面类型和加载 MDX 数据到 body 字段。
our docs page type and
load MDX data into the body field.
然后从文件系统中获取所有其他的数据,
And then get all the other data, from
the front matter, from the file system,
在一种简单的节点 API 的一个地方，所以我们不做任何事情。
all in one place in one kind of simple
node API so that we're not doing anything.
我们不想在我们的业务逻辑中做所有这些变通方法。
We don't wanna have to do all these
workarounds in our business logic.
我们想设置一次，然后有简单的查询
We wanna set this up once and
then have simple queries for
前端开发人员使用。
the frontend developers to use.
所以如果我停下来重新开始，现在为了这样做，因为我们刚刚改变了
So if I stop and restart, and now in
order to do this, because we just changed
按照节点的工作方式，我们想让盖茨比重新开始。
the way that nodes work, we're going to
want to get Gatsby to pull a fresh start.
所以为了做到这一点，我们要让盖茨比干干净净。
So to do that,
we're gonna run gatsby clean.
但是你把盖茨比打扫得干干净净
But the way that you run gatsby clean and
纱线工作区是我们实际上要做纱线工作区主题-dev。
yarn workspaces is we're actually
gonna do yarn workspace theme-dev.
然后我可以在这个上下文中执行一个任意的命令。
And then I can just execute an arbitrary
command within the context of that.
所以我想把盖茨比打扫干净。
So I wanna run gatsby clean.
它将删除公共目录和缓存目录，以便
And it's going to remove the public and
cache directory so
我们基本上是从零开始。
that we're basically
starting from scratch.
因此，我可以运行纱线工作空间主题开发。
So then I can run yarn
workspace theme-dev develop.
假设一切顺利,
And assuming all went well,
接下来会发生的是，这将启动与我们的 GraphQL 层在适当的地方。
what will happen is this is gonna boot
up with our GraphQL layer in place.
这样我们就可以真正查询我们的主页了。
And we will be able to actually query for
our homepage.
现在我们有了文档页面。
So now we've got our docs pages.
这些都是我们告诉它的数据，对吧？
And those are pulling out the data
that we told it to, right?
所以现在我们的 GraphQL 层有了自定义数据
So now we've got custom data
coming in to our GraphQL layer
使用各种不同的节点作为数据。
using a variety of
different nodes as data.
所以我们使用文件系统。
So we're using the file system.
我们正在使用为路径创建的自定义数据。
We're using custom data that
we're creating for the path.
我们使用 MDX 数据作为身体场。
And we're using the MDX data for
the body field.
这些都是透明的，或者
This is all kind of transparent, or
这些都是对任何人隐藏起来的。
this is all kind of hidden from
anybody who has to implement this.
他们只知道我需要文档数据，他们也得到了。
They just know I want docs data,
and they get it.
所以他们甚至不需要关心这是否来自 MDX。
So they don't even have to
care that this comes from MDX.
他们只是需要有数据来使用。
They just need to have data to use.
让我们稍微看一下，很多事情是如何完成的
And to look a little bit at kind of
how this a lot of things get done for
我们，让我们从现在开始设置为真。
us, let's just set from now to true.
这是一个内置的帮助器来做相对时间。
And this is a built in
helper to do relative time.
所以现在我们可以看到它给了我们这个时间戳。
So right now we can see it
gave us this time stamp.
有点小。
It's a little small.
让我们把它放大一点。
So let's make that a little bigger.
如果我把它改成从现在开始等于真，然后点击播放。
And if I change it to from
now equals true and hit play.
现在它给了我们一个相对的变化。
Now it gives us a relative change.
41分钟前是最后一次修改这个文档。
So 41 minutes ago was the last time
that this document was changed.
所以当我们在网站上展示这个的时候，我们可以用简单的英语。
So we can just use that in plain English
when we display this on the site.
我们只改变盖茨比节点。
We only change the Gatsby node.
所以，让我们加上这一点。
So let's add that.
然后我们提交(theme-dev) : 添加模式定制。
And then we'll commit (theme-dev):
add schema customization.
让我来推一下。
And let me push that.
所以这一切都被推到了回购协议上的进步分支
And so this is all being pushed to
the fen-progress branch on the repo if
你想重新回到我们在任何时刻所处的位置。
you want to kind of reset to
where we are at any given moment.